Guide to the Abe Fortas Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence and Topical Files, 1935-1983; Series II
  - Douglas, William O.
    See also: Freund Report (Study Group on the Caseload of the Supreme Court); Porter, Paul A.; Rodell, Fred; Series III. Articles--"The Fifth Amendment: Nemo Tenetur Prodere Seipsum"; "Sacco, Vanzetti -- and Justice"; "Mr. Justice Douglas"; "The Constitution and the Presidency"; "Chief Justice Warren: The Enigma of Leadership"; "William O. Douglas: A Eulogy"; Speeches--Implications of Durham's Case, American Psychiatric Association; Series VI. American Red Magen David for Israel, Tribute to Emanuel Celler; Washington School of Psychiatry
    - September [1936]-February 1959 (Box 105, Folder 106 - 108)
    - March 1959-March 1982 (Box 106, Folder 109 - 114)
    - Douglas Anniversary Convocation, 1973 (Box 106, Folder 115)
    - Financial materials, 1977-1980 (Box 106, Folder 116)
    - "Inquiry into the State of Individual Freedom" [includes photographs]
      - February 1977-September 1978 (Box 106, Folder 117 - 119)
      - October 1978-April 1982 (Box 107, Folder 120 - 122)
    - Memorial service, 1980-1981 (Box 107, Folder 123 - 125)
    - 1948 presidential campaign, 1947-1948 (Box 107, Folder 126 - 127)
    - Of Men and Mountains, 1949-1950 (Box 107, Folder 128)
    - Supreme Court of the United States [Memorial Resolutions]
      - June 1980-September 1980 (Box 107, Folder 129)
      - October 1980-January 1981 (Box 108, Folder 130 - 131)
  - Dulles, John Foster
  - Durr, Clifford J. and Virginia, 1975-1976 (Box 108, Folder 132)
    See also: Series IV. Durr, Clifford and Virginia
  - E, 1960-1982 (Box 108, Folder 133)
  - Eaton, Cyrus S., 1957-1980 (Box 108, Folder 134)
    See also: Douglas, William O.; Series III. Articles--"'Anti-trust' in the United States"; "Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal--D-G; Moyers, William; State, Department of
  - Eban, Abba
    See: Kenneth B. Keating Institute of American Studies
  - Eichholz, Mercedes and Robert B., 1965-1981 (Box 108, Folder 135)
    See also: Douglas, William O--Memorial service; Douglas, William O.--Supreme Court of the United States [Memorial Resolutions]; Hirshhorn, Joseph H.; Series III. Speeches--To Fulfill the Constitution, Ohio State University College of Law
  - Ellberger, Ronald E., 1968-1979 (Box 108, Folder 136)
    See also: Warren, Earl
  - Elman, Philip, 1961-1971 (Box 108, Folder 137)
  - Ely, John Hart
    See: Gideon v. Wainwright --Notes and memoranda
  - Emerson, Thomas I.
    See: Douglas, William O.; Douglas, William O.-- Douglas Anniversary Convocation, "Inquiry into the State of Individual Freedom," Memorial service, Supreme Court of the United States [Memorial Resolutions]; Yale Law School, Course in "Legal Principles of Competitive Economics"
  - Erbe, Gary T. [includes photographs], 1974 (Box 108, Folder 138)
  - Ervin, Sam J., Jr.
    See: Presidential impoundment of funds; Series III. Speeches--The Rule in Durham's Case, Federal Bar Association; Series IV. Federal Bureau of Investigation
  - Eskin (Rubottom), Virginia [includes photograph], 1964-1981 (Box 108, Folder 139)
  - Fa-Fi [includes photograph], 1956-1981 (Box 109, Folder 140)
  - Fain, Mary, 1946-1981 (Box 109, Folder 141)
  - Farber, Sidney
    See: Agger, Donald; Fa-Fi
  - Fasteau, Marc S., 1969 (Box 109, Folder 142)
  - Federated Department Stores
    See: Lazarus, Fred, Jr.; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal--S-Z
  - Feinberg, Abraham
  - Fernós-Isern, A.
  - Ferrer, José
    See: Casals, Pablo and Marta
  - Finkelstein, Louis
    See: Jewish Theological Seminary
  - Fl-Free [includes photograph], 1960-1982 (Box 109, Folder 143)
  - Fleming, Arthur S., Awards, 1967-1968 (Box 109, Folder 144)
  - Fonda, Henry
    See: Gideon, Clarence Earl
  - Ford, Gerald R.
    See: Douglas, William O.; Series VI. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts--Bicentennial Theater Festival
  - Fortas, Henry, 1961-1966 (Box 109, Folder 145)
  - Fortas, Midge and Meyer, 1944-1980 (Box 109, Folder 146)
  - Fortas, Milton, 1961-1965 (Box 109, Folder 147)
  - Fortas, Ray, 1943-1947 (Box 109, Folder 148)
  - Fortas, Samores, 1961-1966 (Box 109, Folder 149)
    See also: Series III. Speeches--Not a New Deal But a New Zeal;Series VI.Federated Department St
  - Fortas, William E. and family, 1956-1982 (Box 109, Folder 150)
    See also: Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal)--D-G; Speeches--Law Day, Memphis State University School of Law; [No title], Congregation Ohebai Shalom, Memphis, Tennessee
  - Fortes, David, 1966-1978 (Box 109, Folder 151)
  - Fortes, Meyer and family, 1955-1982 (Box 109, Folder 152 - 153)
    See also: Series III. Articles--"The Fifth Amendment: Nemo Tenetur Prodere Seipsum"; Speeches--[No title], David Niles Lecture, Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1969
  - Fortes, Natalie, 1959-1961 (Box 109, Folder 154)
  - Fortes, Neil, 1973-1976 (Box 109, Folder 155)
  - Frank, Barbara R., 1979-1982 (Box 109, Folder 156)
  - Frank, Jerome N., 1955-1969 (Box 109, Folder 157)
    See also: Douglas, William O.; Series III. Articles--"The Fifth Amendment: Nemo Tenetur Prodere Seipsum"
  - Frank, John P., 1961-1980 (Box 109, Folder 158 - 159)
    See also: Clark, Ramsey; Douglas, William O.; Douglas, William O.--1948 presidential campaign, Memorial service, Supreme Court of the United States [Memorial Resolutions]; Series III. Articles--"Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Speeches--Constitution--Conscience--Communism, American Law Institute
  - Frankfurter, Felix
    See: Clemens, Cyril; Series III. Speeches--Implications of Durham's Case, American Psychiatric Association
  - Freeman, Milton V.
    See: Yale Law School, Course in "Legal Principles of Competitive Economics"; Series III. Articles--"Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal--D-G; Ethics in the Executive Branch
  - Fren-Fu, 1956-1973 (Box 109, Folder 160)
  - Freund, Paul A.
    See: Benítez, Jaime and family; Series III. Speeches--The Role of Counsel for the Witness in a Public Investigation, Harvard Student Bar Association
  - Freund Report [Study Group on the Caseload of the Supreme Court], 1972-1973 (Box 110, Folder 161)
  - Friday Morning Music Club, Inc., 1973-1982 (Box 110, Folder 162)
  - Friedman & Koven, personal correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 110, Folder 163)
    See also: Series III. Speeches--The Constitution and the Presidency, Young Lawyers Section, Chicago Bar Association; Age Discrimination Under Federal Law, National Conference on Age and Employment
  - Friendly, Henry J.
    See: Series III. Speeches--The Training of the Practitioner, Rutgers University, School of Law; Series VI. Institute of Judicial Administration, Project on Anglo-American Administrative Law; Judicial Conference of the United States, Advisory Committee on Appellate Rules
  - Fuchs, Ralph F.
    See: Series VI. Administrative Conference of the United States, Committee on Personnel; Washington School of Psychiatry
  - Ga-Ge [includes photograph], 1956-1981 (Box 110, Folder 164)
  - Gahrout, Marianne [includes photograph], 1955-1981 (Box 110, Folder 165)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth
    See: Harris, Elizabeth Forsling; Series III. Articles--"The Constitution and the Presidency"
  - Garrison, Lloyd K.
    See: Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton & Garrison; Series IV. Judicial appointments
  - Gellhorn, Walter, 1957-1970 (Box 110, Folder 166)
    See also: Series III. Articles--"Outside the Law"; "The Fifth Amendment: Nemo Tenetur Prodere Seipsum"; Speeches--[No title], Judicial Conference of the Second Circuit; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal--D-G; Judicial appointments; Series VI. Administrative Conference of the United States, Committee on Personnel
  - Gessell, Gerhard A., 1980
    See: Douglas, William O.--Supreme Court of the United States [Memorial Resolutions]; Series VI. President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity in the Armed Forces
  - Gi, 1959-1982 (Box 110, Folder 167)
  - Gideon, Clarence Earl, 1962-1982 (Box 110, Folder 168)
    See also: Graham, Fred P.
  - Gideon v. Wainwright [or Gideon v. Cochran ]
    - Background and research materials, 1962-1963 (Box 110, Folder 169 - 172)
    - Briefs, 1962-1963 (Box 111, Folder 173 - 174)
    - Court papers, 1962-1963 (Box 111, Folder 175 - 177)
    - Notes and memoranda, 1962-1963 (Box 111, Folder 178)
    - Printed materials, 1962-1977 (Box 111, Folder 179 - 180)
    - Printed materials, 1962-1977 (Box 112, Folder 181 - 182)
    - Related materials, 1962-1963 (Box 112, Folder 183)
  - Gideon v. Wainwright, Encyclopedia Britannica Films, 1965-1966 (Box 112, Folder 184)
  - Gillers, Stephen
    See: Douglas, William O.--Douglas Anniversary Convocation
  - Gilmore, Grant
    See: Alschuler, Martha F.
  - Ginsburg, David
    See: Douglas, William O.; Douglas, William O.--Douglas Anniversary Convocation, "Inquiry into the State of Individual Freedom," 1948 presidential campaign; Gi; Harris, Elizabeth Forsling; Israel trip; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal--D-G; Inaugural Concert 1965
  - Gl-Gu [includes photographs], 1956-1981 (Box 112, Folder 185)
  - Goldberg, Arthur J., 1962-1971 (Box 112, Folder 186)
    See also: Douglas, William O.--Supreme Court of the United States [Memorial Resolutions]; Series III. Speeches--[No title], The Massachusetts Committee of Catholics, Protestants, and Jews; [No title], David Niles Lecture, Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1969; Series IV. Arnold, Thurman Wesley; Blaustein, Jacob; crime; Series VI. President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity
  - Goldschmidt, Arthur ("Tex") and Elizabeth Wickenden Goldschmidt, 1957-1982 (Box 112, Folder 187)
    See also: Gideon v. Wainwright, Background and research materials; Series III. Speeches--Equal Rights -- For Whom?, James Madison Lecture, New York University School of Law; "Lyndon Johnson," New York Times
  - Goldstein, Abraham S.
    See: Burson, Harold and family; charitable contributions; Yale Law School; Yale University library
  - Goldstein, E. Ernest, 1968-1979 (Box 112, Folder 188)
    See also: Casals, Pablo and Marta; Porter, Paul A. and Kathleen Winsor; Series III. Articles--"Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"
  - González, Pedro A., 1960-1971 (Box 112, Folder 189)
  - Gorman, Mike, 1966-1968 (Box 112, Folder 190)
    See also: Agger, Donald; President's Commission on Cancer, Heart Disease, and Stroke
  - Graham, Fred P., 1965-1969 (Box 112, Folder 191)
  - Graham, Katherine, 1967-1968 (Box 112, Folder 192)
  - Green, Edith
    See: Series III. Speeches--[No title], the Vice-Presidency [background materials only], 1973-1974
  - Griffiths, John, 1966-1968 (Box 112, Folder 193)
  - Griswold, Erwin N.
    See: Burson, Harold and family; Series III. Speeches--The Role of Counsel for the Witness in a Public Investigation, Harvard Student Bar Association; Articles--"The Fifth Amendment: Nemo Tenetur Prodere Seipsum"; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal--D-G
  - Grzesnikowski, Barbara and Edwin, 1966-1980 (Box 112, Folder 194)
  - Gulliver, Ashbel
    See: District of Columbia Bar Examination
  - Haas, Saul, 1950-1972 (Box 112, Folder 195)
    See also: Douglas, William O.; Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal), H-K; Articles--"Outside the Law"
  - Had-Hart [includes photograph], 1956-1982 (Box 112, Folder 196)
  - Hadley, Arlene B.
    See: District of Columbia Bar Examination; Yale Law School, Course in "Legal Principles of Competitive Economics"
  - Haldeman, H. R.
    See: Series VI. Kennedy Center--General correspondence
  - Halle, Kay
    See also: Derenberg, Walter J.; Had-Hart
  - Hamilton, Dagmar S.
    See: Douglas, William O.--Supreme Court of the United States [Memorial Resolutions]
  - Hamilton, Fowler
    See: Arnold, Thurman Wesley; Cox, Hugh Baker; Hoffman, Louis; Series III. Articles--"Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Series IV. Arnold, Thurman Wesley
  - Hamilton, Walton Hale, 1958-1959 (Box 112, Folder 197)
    See also: Porter, Paul A.; Yale Law School, Course in "Legal Principles of Competitive Economics"; Series III. Articles--"An American Land Policy"; Series VI. Washington School of Psychiatry
  - Hammer, Jane
    See: Friday Morning Music Club, Inc.
  - Harlan, John Marshall, 1966-1968 (Box 112, Folder 198)
    See also: Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal), H-K; Speeches--[No title], Yale Law School Association of Washington, D.C.; [No title], Judicial Conference of the First Circuit, 1968
  - Harman, Avraham
    See: Had-Hart; Israel trip; Series III. Speeches-- [No title], Hebrew University of Jerusalem; [No title], David Niles Lecture, Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1969
  - Harper, Fowler V.
    See: Rostow, Eugene V.; Series III. Articles--"Puerto Rico: Problem Child"; Speeches--Invitations to speak, 1946-1947
  - Harris, Elizabeth Forsling, 1962-1973 (Box 112, Folder 199)
    See also: Linowitz, Sol M.
  - Hart, Allan
  - Harte, Houston, 1961-1972 (Box 113, Folder 200)
    See also: Porter, Paul A.
  - Harv-Hay, 1965-1981 (Box 113, Folder 201)
  - Haskell, Floyd K.
    See: Charitable contributions
  - Hastie, William H.
    See: Series VI. Judicial Conference of the United States, Advisory Committee on Appellate Rules
  - Hatfield, Mark O.
    See: Bloch, Ernest and family
  - He-Hi, 1957-1981 (Box 113, Folder 202)
  - Healy, Timothy S.
    See: Brooks, Joseph E.
  - Heckscher, August
    See: Linowitz, Sol M.
  - Hellman, Lillian
    See: Series III. Articles--"The Fifth Amendment: Nemo Tenetur Prodere Seipsum"
  - Hernández-Colón, Rafael, 1971-1982 (Box 113, Folder 203)
  - Herzberg, Ben, 1961-1969 (Box 113, Folder 204)
    See also: Zimroth, Peter L.
  - Hessler, Curtis Alan, 1981 (Box 113, Folder 205)
  - Heyworth, Geoffrey and Laurence, 1956-1960 (Box 113, Folder 206)
    See also: Lever Brothers
  - Higginbotham, A. Leon, Jr.
    See: Series III. Speeches--Prayer Breakfast, American College of Trial Lawyers, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
  - Hirshhorn, Joseph H. [includes photographs], 1960-1981 (Box 113, Folder 207 - 210)
  - Hitchcock, Maxine
    See: Colorado Music Festival; He-Hi
  - Ho-Hu, 1956-1981 (Box 113, Folder 211)
  - Hoffman, Louis, 1956-1968 (Box 113, Folder 212)
    See also: Series III. Articles--"Lyndon Johnson"; Speeches--[No title], Constitution Day, San Juan, Puerto Rico
  - Holcomb, Luther, 1969-1971 (Box 113, Folder 213)
  - Homelson family, 1972 (Box 113, Folder 214)
  - Honorary memberships, 1965-1969 (Box 113, Folder 215)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1970 (Box 113, Folder 216)
  - Hornyak, Eva, 1977-1978 (Box 113, Folder 217)
  - Hoyt, E. Palmer, 1955-1975 (Box 113, Folder 218)
    See also: Douglas, William O.--Douglas Anniversary Convocation
  - Humane treatment of animals, 1963-1968 (Box 113, Folder 219)
  - Hummel, Jerri Roberts Shafer [includes photograph], 1961-1971 (Box 113, Folder 220)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1960-1977 (Box 113, Folder 221)
    See also: Douglas, William O.--1948 presidential campaign; Stern, Isaac and Vera; Series III. Speeches--[No title], the Vice-Presidency [background materials only], 1973-1974; Israel: The Problem and the Promise, Beth Sholom Congregation, Washington, D.C.
  - Hutchins, Robert Maynard
    See: Douglas, William O.; Douglas, William O.--"Inquiry into the State of Individual Freedom"; Ho-Hu; T; Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal); Articles--"Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Speeches--Introductory remarks, American Veterans Committee; Series IV. Kennedy assassination, John F.
  - Huxley, Julian S.
    See: Series VI. Washington School of Psychiatry
  - I, 1962-1981 (Box 114, Folder 222)
  - Ickes, Harold L. and Jane
    See: Agger, Donald; Douglas, William O.--1948 presidential campaign; I; McNally, James W.; Travel itineraries and receipts; Series III. Speeches--Commission on the Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians; Series V. Government Service
  - Inter-American Music Festival, 1978-1980 (Box 114, Folder 223)
  - International Center for Dynamics of Development, 1978-1979 (Box 114, Folder 224)
  - Israel
    See also: Bar-On, Hanan; Had-Hart
  - Israel trip, 1974 (Box 114, Folder 225)
  - Istomin, Eugene and Marta Casals Istomin, 1976-1981 (Box 114, Folder 226)
    See also: Casals, Pablo and Marta; Series IV. Humphrey, Hubert H.; Series VI. Kennedy Center, Institute/conservatory for the performing arts
  - J, 1961-1981 (Box 114, Folder 227)
  - Jackson, Henry M. "Scoop"
    See: Charitable contributions; J
  - Janak, Tony, 1971-1973 (Box 114, Folder 228)
    See also: Series VIII. Audiovisual Materials
  - Jenkins, Walter
    See: J; Agger, Donald; Series III. Speeches--[No title], University of Texas at Austin, 1970; Series IV. Jenkins, Walter
  - Jewish Theological Seminary, 1966-1970 (Box 114, Folder 229)
    See also: Johnson, Lady Bird; Series III. Speeches--The Responsibilities of Politics, The Jewish Theological Seminary of America; [No title], Convocation, Jewish Theological Seminary, 1965
  - Johnson, Lady Bird, 1961-1981 (Box 114, Folder 230)
    See also: Johnson, Lyndon Baines; Johnson, Lyndon Baines, LBJ Library; Stern, Isaac and Vera; Series III. Articles--"Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Series IV. Johnson, Lady Bird
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines [includes photographs], 1955-1982, undated (Box 114, Folder 231 - 235)
    See also: Ab-Am; Agger, Donald; Ba; Cousins, Norman; Douglas, William O.; Leventhal, Harold; Smith, Charles E.; Verity, C. William, Jr.; Yale Law School; Series III. Articles--"Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Series IV. White House Papers
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines, LBJ Library, 1971-1977 (Box 114, Folder 236)
    See also: Johnson, Lady Bird
  - Jones, James R., 1974 (Box 114, Folder 237)
  - Juvenile justice, 1967-1975 (Box 115, Folder 238)
  - Ka, 1960-1981 (Box 115, Folder 239)
  - Kahn, Albert E.
  - Kalven, Harry
    See: Marcus, Stanley and family; Series III. Speeches--Insanity and the Law, University of Chicago; The Training of the Practitioner, Rutgers University, School of Law; Series VI. University of Chicago, School of Law
  - Kaplan, J. M. and family, 1965-1982 (Box 115, Folder 240)
    See also: Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal), H-K; Series IV. Advisory Council on the Arts
  - Karsten, Thomas L., 1961-1982 (Box 115, Folder 241)
    See also: Series IV. Correspondence--Personal-- H-L
  - Katzenbach, Nicholas deB., 1962-1968 (Box 115, Folder 242)
    See also: Weisl, Edwin L.
  - Ke, 1958-1982 (Box 115, Folder 243)
  - Keating, Kenneth
    See: Israel trip
  - Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts
    See: Casals, Pablo and Marta; Schneider, Alexander; Stern, Isaac and Vera
  - Kennedy, Edward M.
    See: Benítez, Jaime and family; Casals, Pablo and Marta; charitable contributions; Ke; Series VI. Kennedy Center, Kennedy family; Studio/Terrace Theater
  - Kennedy, Jacqueline, 1967 (Box 115, Folder 244)
    See also: Series VI. Kennedy Center, Kennedy family
  - Kennedy, John F.
    See: Series VI. President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity in the Armed Forces
  - Kennedy, Robert F.
    See: Herzberg, Ben
  - Kennedy Smith, Jean
    See: Series VI. Kennedy Center, Kennedy family; Studio/Terrace Theater
  - Kenneth B. Keating Institute of American Studies, 1977-1978 (Box 115, Folder 245)
  - Kerbel family, 1957-1976 (Box 115, Folder 246)
  - Ketcham, Orman W., 1955-1967 (Box 115, Folder 247)
  - Keyserling, Leon H., 1956-1969 (Box 115, Folder 248)
    See also: Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal), H-K; Articles--"Outside the Law"; "Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Series IV. President's Council of Economic Advisers
  - Ki-Ky, [ca. 1956]-1982 (Box 115, Folder 249)
  - Kintner, Robert E., 1966-1968 (Box 115, Folder 250)
  - Kirchwey, Freda
    See: Palestine
  - Kirk, H. L.
    See: Casals, Pablo and Marta; Series III. Speeches--An Appreciation: 1968 Freedom House Award to Pablo Casals, New York, New York
  - Kirks, Rowland F.
  - Kissinger, Nancy M.
  - Kizer, Carolyn [includes photograph], 1959-1966 (Box 115, Folder 251)
  - Kollek, Teddy, 1967-1978 (Box 115, Folder 252)
    See also: Israel trip
  - Koven, Howard R.
    See: Derenberg, Walter J.; Douglas, William O.--Supreme Court of the United States [Memorial Resolutions]; Friedman & Koven, personal correspondence; Johnson, Lyndon Baines
  - Kramer, Victor H.
    See: Arnold, Thurman Wesley; Ki-Ky; Series III. Articles--"America's Electrical Price Conspiracy"; Speeches--The Grievances of the Small Business Man -- A Bill of Particulars, American Bar Association Section on Antitrust Laws; Portents for New Anti-Trust Policy, Corporate Counsel Institute; [No title], American Bar Association, Section of Antitrust Law, 1966; [No title], American College of Trial Lawyers, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1968; Invitations to speak or write, 1970-1972; [No title], Georgetown Law Journal, Georgetown University Law Center; Series VI. Administrative Conference of the United States, Committee on Personnel
  - Krash, Abe
    See: Baker, Robert ("Bobby") G.; Casals, Pablo and Marta; Gideon v. Wainwright; Ki-Ky; Series III. Articles--"Sacco, Vanzetti--and Justice"; "Thurman Arnold and the Theater of Law"; Speeches--Justifications Under the Robinson-Patman Act, University of Cincinnati College of Law; Durham decision; The Defense of Insanity in a Criminal Case, American Bar Association; Introductory remarks, American Veterans Committee; Interrelationships Between Law and Psychiatry, Washington Psychiatric Society; The law and psychiatry; Series IV. Ethics in the Executive Branch
  - Kreeger, David Lloyd, 1966-1980 (Box 115, Folder 253)
    See also: Benítez, Jaime and family; Stern, Isaac and Vera; Trías Monge, José; Series III. Speeches--[No title], Edwin A. Mooers Lecture, Washington College of Law, American University; Series IV. Correspondence--Personal--H-L; Series VI. National Symphony Orchestra; Marlboro School of Music
  - Krim, Arthur and Mathilde, 1970-1981 (Box 115, Folder 254)
    See also: Israel trip; Johnson, Lyndon Baines; McGovern, George; Mu; Sa-Sc; Series III. Articles--"Lyndon Johnson"
  - Kronheim, Milton S.
    See: Stern, Isaac and Vera; Series IV. Judicial appointments; Series VI. Federated Department Stores
  - Kvarnes, Robert G.
  - La, 1956-1981 (Box 115, Folder 255)
  - Lach, Benjamin
    - June 1971-June 1976 (Box 115, Folder 256)
    - July 1976-July 1979 (Box 116, Folder 257)
  - Lane, Robert M., 1961-1972 (Box 116, Folder 258)
    See also: Series IV. Moyers, William; Valenti, Jack
  - Laredo, Jaime and Ruth [includes photograph], 1968-1979 (Box 116, Folder 259)
  - Lasker, Mary
    See: Agger, Donald; La; Series IV. Inaugural Concert 1965
  - Lattimore, Owen, 1961-1981 (Box 116, Folder 260)
    See also: de Baat, M.G.; Series III. Speeches--Checks and Balances -- Or Checkmate? A Bicentennial Summation, College of Mount St. Joseph
  - Lazarus, Fred, Jr., 1958-1973 (Box 116, Folder 261)
    See also: Douglas, William O.; Resignation, letters of; Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal), L-R; Articles--"'Anti-trust' in the United States"; Speeches--The Responsibilities of Politics, The Jewish Theological Seminary of America; [No title], American College of Trial Lawyers, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1968; Checks and Balances -- Or Checkmate? A Bicentennial Summation, College of Mount St. Joseph; Series IV. Lazarus family
  - Lazarus, Maurice, 1962-1969 (Box 116, Folder 262)
    See also: Series III. Books-- Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience, Correspondence (personal), L-R; Articles--"Outside the Law"; Series IV. Lazarus family